Abhinav Gupta

Digital Product Designer

www.itsabhi.com abhinav191@gmail.com +91-9971201670

A multi-disciplinary designer with 5+ years of domain experience in designing and developing for enterprise and consumer grade applications to create meaningful and easy to use products.

Self motivated with keen interest in making simple, clean and clear designs. Always on a look-out for new technologies and trends.

Work Experience

VMware - Product Designer III

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT, BANGALORE

Helping shape up experiences for the flagship product VMware vRealize Automation - a powerful and easy-to-use Infrastructure Automation Platform.

Currently the only designer from India for the team driving forward the initiative for providing a consumer grade experience to our users.

SAP - UX Designer

JULY 2018 - OCTOBER 2019, BANGALORE

Worked as the Lead Designer from Bangalore location to create unified experiences for the internal tools development team. Extensive collaboration with Design teams, Product Managers and Developers from global locations for user research, testing, design reviews and driving local and global projects forward.

SAP - UX Design Intern

JULY 2017 - JANUARY 2018, BANGALORE

Worked on complete re-design of an internal online collaboration tool for teams within SAP while defining a common design language for future tools to be developed.

Group10 Tech. - Sr. Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2012 - JUNE 2015, GURGAON

Worked with front-end technologies like HTML,CSS and Javascript and frameworks like Drupal to make websites and applications for the client providing an easy to use and simple user experience and defining and streamlining the process of making applications.

Education

National Institute of Design

MASTER OF DESIGN (M.DES)
INFORMATION DESIGN
2015-2017, BANGALORE

Indraprastha University

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.TECH)
INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
2008-2012, DELHI

Skills

Design: UX Design, Interaction Design, User Research, Usability Testing, UI Design, Information Architecture, Motion Design, Graphic Design, Data Visualisation

Tools: Figma, Sketch, Framer, Principle, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects, Adobe InDesign

Technology: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Git